<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LK99 on LEl_FENG Blog</title><link>https://blog.xpdbk.com/en/tags/lk99/</link><description>Recent content in LK99 on LEl_FENG Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>XiaoPang版权所有</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:21:58 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.xpdbk.com/en/tags/lk99/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LK 99 Is this superconductor fake?</title><link>https://blog.xpdbk.com/en/post/lk99-superconductor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:21:58 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.xpdbk.com/en/post/lk99-superconductor/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="lk-99-a-controversial-claim-of-room-temperature-superconductivity">LK-99: A Controversial Claim of Room-Temperature Superconductivity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Superconductivity is the phenomenon of zero electrical resistance and expulsion of magnetic fields in certain materials when they are cooled below a critical temperature. Superconductors have many applications, such as magnetic resonance imaging, quantum computing, and high-speed trains. However, most superconductors require extremely low temperatures (below -200 °C) and high pressures to operate, which limits their practical use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, we introduce LK-99, a novel material that claims to be a superconductor at room temperature and ambient pressure. LK-99 is a mix of powdered compounds of lead, oxygen, sulphur and phosphorus. When it is heated at very high temperatures, it forms a dark grey solid. According to the new research, the material exhibits some of the common characteristics of superconductors, such as zero resistivity, critical current, and a critical magnetic field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LK-99 was first discovered and manufactured by a team of researchers including Sukbae Lee and Ji-Hoon Kim from Korea University. The team claims that LK-99 functions as a superconductor at ambient pressure and below 400 K (127 °C; 260 °F). As of 3 August 2023, the synthesis of LK-99 and observation of its superconductivity at any temperature have not been peer-reviewed or independently replicated. The announcement was widely shared and the reaction by the scientific world was mainly skeptical due to the extraordinary nature of the claims, the repeated failure of previous claims of room-temperature superconductors, and errors and inconsistencies in the pre-published papers. Independent teams are attempting to replicate the South Korean team&amp;rsquo;s work, with results expected in August 2023 owing to the straightforward method of producing the material.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The claim of LK-99 has also sparked a race among DIY enthusiasts and amateur scientists to reproduce the experiment at home or in their labs. Some of them have posted videos on Bilibili, a Chinese video-sharing platform, showing their attempts to synthesize LK-99 and test its magnetic properties. One of the most popular videos was posted by an account named &amp;ldquo;Guan Shan Kou Male Technician&amp;rdquo;, who claimed to have successfully synthesized LK-99 crystals that can levitate over a magnet with a larger angle than the original paper. However, he also said that he still needs to verify the electrical resistance to confirm the superconductivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The claim of LK-99 has also received some support from theoretical calculations. A team from Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory in the US published a paper on arXiv, claiming that they have found the theoretical basis for the superconductivity of copper-doped lead phosphate apatite, which is the structure of LK-99. They used computer models to describe the characteristics that a room-temperature superconductor should have, and found that LK-99 matches those criteria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If confirmed, LK-99 would be a breakthrough in the field of superconductivity and could have a huge impact on many industries, such as electronics, energy, and transportation. However, until then, LK-99 remains a controversial and unverified claim that needs further investigation and validation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>